Finding Aid for the Norman Cousins Papers LSC.1385
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Volume 1
  - Document Case #60. Personal and Business Correspondence.
    - 2. Folder. - C-E., 1941 (Box 316)
      (John Campbell, Cortland Canby, Edward Canby, Henry Canby, Carl Cannon, Cardiff, Paul Carre, Bennett Cerf, John [UNK] W.H.Chamberlain, Frederick Chase, Richard S. Childs, V.L.O.Chittick, Erwin Canham, Allen Churchill, Donald Clark, John Abbot Clark, Freeman Cleeves, James Clifford, Upton Close, Gardner Clouch, Wilson [UNK] Ernest Calkins; Erskine Caldwell, L.N. Calahan, George Coffman, A.P. Coleman, Agatha Collins, Howard Collins, L.R.Connor, S.V. Constant, [UNK] Cooke, Miss Mary CooleyEleanor S. Cooper, Cooper Union Forum, Irene Cooper, Edward Corwin, John O'Hara Cosgrave, Ben Cossart, Richard Costa, Thoman Cottan, Miriam Breen, Robert Cousins, Alexander Cowie, John aCowles, Malcolm Cowley, Joan Coyne, Cheryl Crawford, W.D. Crocker, Ken Crossen, Lewis Curtis, Sewell Haggard, Curtis Brown Ltd., John Campbell, Lib. of Congress, George Dalzell, George Dangerfield, Kedarnath Das Gupta, [UNK] Davenport, Hassoldt David, Isidore Davidson, Elmer Davis, Clarence Day, John Defandorf, Marie Driscall, David Dempsey, Leon Dennen, George Denny, August Derleth, Eric Devine, Gertrude Diamant, JP Didier, EJ Dintroff, Robert Disraeli, Vera Dodds, Wm Doerflinger, Wm Dogan, Fairfax Downey, Peter Drucker, H. Dudwick, Charles Duell, Edward Duff, Stephan Early Wm Easton, Charles Eaton, Cyrus Eaton, N. Eliot, Paul Ellerbe, Raude Elliot, Ann Elmo, Clark Emery, R.E. Engelsberg, Monroe England, Theodore English, Abraham Epstein, Lloyd Wendell Eshleman.
    - 3. Folder. - F-G., 1941 (Box 316)
      Clifton Fadiman, N.B. Fagin, James Farrell, Charles Feldman, Otis Ferguson, Harold Fields, James Finan, Louis Fischer, Stuyvesant Fish, Dudley Fitts, Wlmer Wm Flaccus, Barthold Fles, Rev. Vincent Flynn, Mrs. Ford Madox Ford, Janice Ford, Harrison Foreman, Henry Ja mes Foreman, Ruth Foster, Douglas Fox, Harry Franck, Justice Felix Frankfurter, Louise Franklin, Joseph Freeman, George Freitag, Constance Frick, Ralph Friedrich, Wm Frierson, G. Fry, R.N. Fuller, Deoch Fulton, Caroline Fuller, Flagler Fultz, Clifton Joseph Funness, James Gallagher, Miriam Gallaher, Joseph Ganther, Harold Gardiner, Martin Gardner, C. Garfield, GR Garrett, Dean Gauss-Princeton U., Norman Bel Geddes, Wm Gekle, John Geoghegan, Philip Gerard, Frank Gerrodette, Leo Gershoy, Jack Ghene, Elsa Gidlow, S. Giedion, Miss Gilman, Wm Gold, Dan Golempaul, NM Goodwin, Donald Gordon, Eleanor Gorham, Herbert Gorman, Rubin Gotesky, Manfred Gottfried, SB Gould, Wm Grace, Hartlay Grattan, John Temple Graves, Leslie Gray, James Gray, George Green, Garland Greever, Annie Greenwood, Marjorie Griesser, H. Griffin, EB Griffith, Frank Gruber, Frederick Gunsky, Bertha Gunterman, Walter Gustafson, Frederick Gutheim, PN Guyol, Harry Gwinner.
    - 4. Folder. - F., 1941 (Box 316)
      Ralph Habas, Sewell Haggard, B. Hall, David Hall, Addison Hallock, Philip Hamburger, Alvin Hamer, WJ Hamilton, Esther Hance, Marius Hansome, Francis Harding, Jane Hardy, Elfrieda Haret, Herbert Harley, Palmer Harman, Harper & Bros., Harrell, Herbert Harris, Leon Harris, Marleine Harris, Joseph Hersch, James Hart, Louis [UNK] Stella Haverland, George Hawley, Sara H. Hay, Albert Hayes, Alvin Hayim, Raymond Healy, Richard Heindel, RW Helprin, Archibald Henderson, Ramona Herdman, Ross Hersey, Max [UNK] Addison Hibbard, Clifford Hicks, Granville Hicks, Maurice Hindus, Milton Hindus, E. Hoberescht, Francis Hodge, Charles Hodge, Raymond Holden, Elizabeth Holding, Mary Holland, Ross Holman, Bernard Holway, Robert Holzman, Louis Homig, EA Hootm, Franz Horch, Horizon, Wm Makins, Joe Horrell, Herbert Hosking, Houghton Mifflin aCo., Wm Houghland, Belford Howard, Paul Hoysradt, Zora Hurston, Fernald Hutchins, A. Huxley, Julian Huxley, Bernard Hyman.
  - Document Case #61. Personal and Business Correspondence.
    - 1. Folder. - I-L., 1941 (Box 316)
      Ickes, Ralph Ingersoll, Inex H Irwin, Christoper Isherwood, Masahito Iwamoto, Henry Jackson, Jacob Jaffe, George Jaffin, Kenneth Jaffray, HC James., Mrs. FH James, Philip James, Wm James, John Jamison, Joseph Jastrow, Grace Keeffe-Jewish [UNK] George Joel, CA Johnson, Isabel Johnston, Claude Jones, Howard M Jones, Rufus Jones, Robert Jordan, Nannine Joseph, Matthew Josephson, [UNK] Kahler, Sholom Kahn, McKnight Kauffer, Samuel Kaufman, Fred Kelly, Mary L Kelly, Arthur Kennedy, ED Kennedy, Stetson Kennedy, WMP Kennedy, Donald Kennicott, John Kern, Thomas Kernan, Chris La Farge, Hirsopp Lake, Jean Lambert, Klaus Lambrecht, Thomas Lamont, Judson Landis, Lang, Oliver Larkin, Cedric Larson, Edwin Larson, Gosta Larsson, Joseph Lash, Lousie Morley, Victor Lasky, Harold Lasswell, Louis Latour, Richard Lauterback, Henry Laurens, Lavelle School for the Blind, Harold Lavine, Don Lawson, Ruth Lawyer, Mrs. N Leachman, Leacock, Pauline Leader, Leslie Learned, Alfred Lee, Constance Lehde, [UNK] Lee. Wm Lengel, Lernau, Max Lerner, Al Lewis, Frederick Lewis, Sinclair Lewis, Willy Lay, Jay Leyda, Stuart Lill RL Limpus, Alex Lindey, Ernest Lindley, G. Lipkind, Lippincott Co., Aktiebloaget Ljus, David Lloyd, Kurt London, Bryand A Long, Harry Long, Stephen Longstreet, Philip Lonsdale, Marie Londobardi, David Lord, Niss HH Lord, Pardee Lowe, Mrs. Henry Luce, Isabel Lundberg, AE Lunder, J. Luzzatto, Harry Lydenberg, Harold Lynch, George Lyon, Mabel D Lyon, Euùgenes Lyons
    - 2. Folder. - M., 1941 (Box 316)
      Mrs. E MacDonald, Wilson MacDonald, Findlay [UNK] Jean Mac Lachlan, MacLeish-Archibald, Rosa Hutchinson,- The Macmillan Co., John Macrae, George Macy, George Dilkes, Lloyd Mallan, John Malony, Ralph Marcellino, Joseph Markin, John Marquand, Miriam Marsh, James Marshall, SLA Marshall, John Martin, Mrs. Arthur Mason, Arthur Moolidge, Richard Match, Harold Matson, Garrett Mattingly, Harry Maule, Andre Maurois, Walter Mayer, GF McCleary, Helen McCloy, Camilla McComber, Neil [UNK] Louise Harrison McCraw, Julia McCune, Helen McDivitt, John McDonald, Wm McFee, George McKay, WK McKee, Nathaniel McKelvey, Theophile J. Meek, Bernard Meland, Lauritz Melchior, Joseph Bachelor-Miami U., Joy Bayless-Methodist Church, Ruth [UNK] Millard, Douglas Miller, Richmond Miller, Mary Mitchell, Harry Thornton Moore, Otis Moore, Christopher Morley, Theodore Morrison, Herbert Muller, Lewis Mumford, Gorham Munson, Helen Munson
    - 3. Folder. - T-Z., 1941 (Box 316)
      Norman Kiell, Miss E. Taggard, Mortiner Taube, Marjorie Taylor, Edmond Taylor, Wm Taylor, Russell Thackrey, LH Titterton, Atwood Townsend, Arthur Tourtellot, Carroll Towle, Frank Trager, Miles Trammell, Anne K. Tuell, Dorothy Norman, Louis Untermeyer, Thomas Usell, Freda Utley, Thomas Uzzell, Herman Ullstein, Mark Van Doren, Hendrick Willem van Loon, Miles Vaughn, The Viking Press, Oswald Garrison Villard, Hugh Mason Wade, Philip Wagner, Nym Wales, Stanley Walker, Margaret Walraven, Mary Walsh, Richard Walsh Jr., Erich Walter, DM Stewart, Ruth Farrar Walton, James Warburg, Vernon Ward, Henry Warfel, Dale Warren, CN Watkins, Goodwin Watson, Carl Weber, Wm Weber, Joseph Wechsberg, Israel SSpanier Wechsler, Harry Wedeck, Edward Weeks, Louis Weinberg, Marcel Weinrich, WL Weiss, Rene' Wellek, Orson Welles, Linton Wells, Martha Wendt, Gerald Wendt, Ives Washburn, John Hall Wheelock, EB White (Mrs.) Mrs..J. Foster White, Robert Whitehand, Milo Whitlatch, Whitman-Ransom-Coulson and Goetz, Thornton Wilder., Albert Williams. Byron Williams, Clarabel Williams, Eleanor Troy Williams, Richmond Williams, Wendell L. Willkie, Winnipeg Free Press Co. Ltd., Robert Withington, EJ Wintringham, Mary Reely-Wisconsin Free Lib. Commission, Joseph Wittlin, Henry Wolfe, Julian Wolff, RE Wolseley, Miriam Wood, Peggy Wood, Weldon Woodson, Lola Worthman, Austin Wright, Cuthbert Wright, Emil Zubryn, Ziemer, Anne Young.
    - 4. Folder. - L1., 1942 (Box 316)
      Cedrid Larson, Gosta Larsson, Bruno Lasker, Augustus Ludwig, Victor Lauriston, HS Latham, J. Laughlin, RS Lawrence, Alfred McClung Lee, Amy Freeman Lee, Henry Lee, Marcia Lee, Wm. Lengel, Florence Becker Lennon, Mauriee Leon, Harold Leorard, Leo Lerman, Max Lerner,.
    - 5. Folder. - L2., 1942 (Box 316)
      Ed Lacy, Llewellyn La Bruce, Oliver La Farge, Juliette Laine, Klaus Lambrecht, Thomas Lamont, Frank Lane, Paul Lang, Leo Lania, Leo Lanier, Fanita Lanier, Cedric Larson, Max Lerner, Albert Rice Leventha, Isaac Don Levine, Jack Lewi, B. Lewis, Bernard Lewis, Jay Leyda, Clars Leiser, Richard Lillard, Edward Lindeman, [UNK] Lindey, Andre' Lion HH Lippincott, Bryant Alden Long, JB Lippincott Co., Lawrence Lipton, Richard Lockridge, Frank Lockwood, Marie Loizeaux, Amy Loreman, Pierre Loving, Faith Mario Loving, Virginia Lowell, Rebecca Lowrie, Mrs. John Lowrie, Flora Ludington, Mildred Lukeman, George Lyon, Gene Lyons
    - 6. Folder. - M., 1942 (Box 316)
      Robert McBride and Co., Coward-McCann, Inc., Buell McCash, Gilbert McClintock, Marion McClure, McFee, Harry Maule, Sidney McGee, Andrew McNally, Paul McNutt, Oscar McPherson, John S Mabon Robert E MacAlarney, Charles Mackintosh, Archibald MacLeish, Fern Maddox, Hugh MacLennan, The Macmillan Co., Magazine Digest, John Magee, P. Magg, Lloyd Mallan, LK Malvern, Conant Manning, Richard Maney, Ronald Mansbridge, WR Manor, Margery Mansfield, Dawes Markwell, AN Marquis Co., Mrs. M Marquis, Marianne Marschak, Bertha Marshall, SLA Marshall, CH Martin, Louis Martin, GE Martling, Martin Matheson, Mary Mathews, Harold Matson, Ernest Matsunaga, G. Mattingly, Charles Maunebach, Andre Maurois, Cliff Maxwell, Ken Macabee, Isaac Mendoza, The Menorah Journal, Dr. HG Merriam, Mrs, Norman Merriam, Hazel Merrimar, Robert Merton, Earl Schenck Miers, Stephen Millard, Edna St. Vincent Millay, Bill Miller, Elizabeth Miller, KM Miller, Mary Miller, WR Miner, Henry Misselwitz, Lilliace Mitchell, Modern Age Books, David Zablodowsky, Modern Industrial Bank, Greg Moller, Lilliam Moltros, Frank Monaghan, Lillian Montecinos, Minnie Hite Moody, William Vaughn Moody, Harry Thornton Moore, John G Moore, Mabel Moore, May Moore, Otis Moore, Dale Morgan, E Winspear, Christopher Morley, Mrs. Dorsey Morris, Jack Morris, Theodore Moffison, [UNK] Morse, Miss L. Morse-Roylett, Robert Moses, Mrs. Murray G Motter, Arnold Mulder, Willard Mullin, Lewis Mumford, Gorham [UNK] Robert Murdock, Tor Myklebost, Moyslyn, Moscow Conference
  - Document Case #62. Personal and Business Correspondence.
    - 1. Folder. - O., 1942 (Box 316)
      Stephen Naft, James Naismith, Gusta Nance, Robert Nathan National Foundation for Education-Samuel Harrell, Carl Naumberg, Walter Naumann, Frank Knox. Charles Neider, Boris Erich Nelson, Arthur Nesbitt, Richard Neuberger, Allan Nevins, Douglas Newman, Rabbi Louis Newman, Adda Newsom, Mr. Newton, New York Dress Inst., Irene Neymeyer, Mrs. Yorke Nicholson, John Nixon, Jr., John Noll, Lindsay Norden, Lewis Nordyke, James Norman, WW Norton, Hayden Norwood, Kathryn O'Brian, Justin O'Brien, Howard Odum, Fredetick Oeshner, Office of Public Relations, Archibald Ogden, Harry Oliphant, Egbert Oliver, Alton O'Steen, Bonaro Overstreet, AM Owens, Russell Owen, E Walsh,- Oxford University.
    - 2. Folder. - P-Q., 1942 (Box 316)
      Mrs. Alexander Page, Mrs. Frank Palmer, Albert Parry, Coleman Parsons, Alma Paschall, Mr. Passaretti, WA Patterson, Dr. PM Payne, William Powell, Post-War World?-Gilbert Cam, SF Porter, Sidney Pomerantz, Lewette Pollock, JH Pollack, ER Pollak, James Sweeny-The Poetry Guild, Edward Podesta, Pocket Books, Inc., Mr. Crayhon-PM Daily, Richard Plant, Frank Place, RE Pierce, Robert Pick, Ben G. Phillips, Dorothy Blair, Wm Phelps, Irving Pflaum, Mary L Pettis, Olga Peterson, Houston Peterson, Charles Peters, Maxwell Perkins, Angus Perkerson, RW Pence, John Pemberton, Jr., Josephine Pemberton, Drew Pearson, NB Pearce, Charles A Pearce, MP Paxton, William Powell, Carroll Pratt, Fletcher Pratt, John L Pratt, Mr. Quinn, Ann Pridky, Prentice-Hall, Press Association, Wm H Price, WC Prime, Print, John W Pritchard, George Pugh, Norma J Pugh, Purdue University, Lawson Purdy, Ruth Putnam, Lucy Putnam Diana Pittman Quarles, Ellery Queen, Margery Quigley, Quote.
    - 3. Folder. - R., 1942 (Box 316)
      Anthony Passaretti-Romeike, Wm Radloff, WM Ramsey, George Randlett, Leah Daniels-Random House, Burton Rascoe, Kenneth Rawlings, B Rector, Ben Ray Redman, Donald [UNK] Helen Reichenbaum, Guenter Reimann, Mary Reinau, George Renard, Emery Reves, George Reynolds, Harold Ribalow, James Ricci, Edwin Rice, Isla Paschal Richardson, Sullivan C Richardson, Barbara Richardson, Vivian Richardson, Dow Richardson, Rose Richter, EV Rickenbacker, Roger Wm Riis, David Ritchie, Mrs. Simpson Ritter, Stewart Robb, Darius Roberts, Ellis Roberts, Dautri Robin, Max Robin, Henry M Robinson, CA Robinson, HB van Wesep-the Rockefeller Foundation, Max Roden, Rodman, Ginger Rogers, John Wm Rogers, Abe Rogow-A Plan for Immediate and Lasting Peace, Jack Rohan, Carl Rollins, Charles Rolo, Jules Romains, Ben Rose, Jean Rose, Rosen, Malcolm Rosholt, Cecil Poole-The [UNK] Rosicrucian Order, Fred Rose, Nathan Rothman, Herman Rovner, Richard Rowan, John Rowe, Edna Rulein, Beatrice Rupp, AW [UNK] David Russell, Wm Russell, Edward Ruten, Stephen Ryan, CT Ryan, Edward Ryan.
    - 4. Folder. - S-1., 1942 (Box 316)
      Anup Singh, John Sise, Bill Slcan, Harold Small, J.H. Small, Charles E Smith, Datus Smith Jr., Dent Smith, Grace Partridge Smith, Jessica Smith, Robert Aura Smith, Norman Smith, Rebecca Smith, Edith Snow, Virginia Smith, Frank Snowden, Carl Snyder, Margaret Snyder, Bernard Sobel, Gilbert Rae Sonbergh, Walter Sorell, Winthrop Southworth, FI Spanayes, Larry Spivak, Walter Spofford, George W Spohn, Claire M Spotswood, John Stainer, Theron Staples, Ada Bell Stapleton, Vincent Starrett, John Steindler, Mrs. Lee R Steiner, Edith Stern, Philip Van Doren Stern, George Stevens, Burton Stevenson, George Stewart, WK Stewart, Dan Stiles, James Stokely, Dillard Stokes, Air Cadet Stone, Phil Stong, Irwin Strouss, Robert Strauz-Hupe, Laura Polanyi Striker, Arthur Stringer, Simeon Strunsky, Charles Stuart, Charles Studin, Thomas Sugrue, Sidney Salkin, Donna Sullivan, Aaron Sussman, Jesse Sutton, Margaret Sutton, [UNK] (AV)
    - 5. Folder. - S-2., 1942 (Box 316)
      Edwin Sabin, IL Salomon, Gaetano Salvemini, Hugh Sanford, Ely Sanger, Stefan Santesson, George B Saul, Mark Saxton, Alfred Sayers, Roger Scaife, FJ Scheerer, Elizabeth Schenck, Harry Scherman, Bernardine Scherman, Joseph Schmedding, Nat Schmulowitz, MB Schnapper, Emily Schossberger, Flora Rheta Schreiber, Paul Schubert, Frederick Schuman, Max Sbhuster, John Schweitzer, Frances Scialy, Hilory Scott, PG Perrin, Frederick Seely, Burr Shafer, Alexander de Seversky, Count Carlo Sforza, Kenneth Shaffer, Dorothy Shapiro, Albert Shaw, Clay Shaw, Mrs. (E) Lenon Shaw, Elton Shaw, Harry Shaw, Roger Shaw, Jack Shay, Lt. Governor Odell Shepard, Douglas Shepardson, Martin Sheridan, Ellen Sherman, Sol Sherman, Mrs. AM Sherwood, AJ Shirley, Francis Shoemaker, [UNK] [UNK] Krishnalal Shridharani, Harry Shriver, George Shuster, Leon [UNK] Mildred Silver, Saul Silvers, Richard Simon, Margaret Simon, OS Sindelka, FA Singer
    - 6. Folder. - T., 1942 (Box 316)
      Mortimer Taube, Herbert Taylor, Ordway [UNK] Leon Tabbetts, Negley Teeters, Miriam Teichner, PW Tell, Musa Tellier, Theatre Library Association, David Thomas, FLR Thomas, Lydia Thomas, Alan Thompson, Malvina Thompson, Stanley Thompson, John Stuart Thomson, Clarence Thorpe, Merle Thorpe, Dorothy Thum, Agnes Tierney, Hugh Tigner, Jane Tiller, Lon Tinkle, LH Titterton, Arthur Tourtellot, Henry C Tracy, Argus Tresidder, Roberta Trigg, Lillian S Troy, Lawrence Tucker, Frank Tully, Jim Tully.
  - Document Case #63. Personal and Business Correspondence.
    - 1. Folder. - U-V., 1942 (Box 316)
      Charles Underhill, Nell Unger, Louis Untermeyer, Anderson-Dewey, University of California, University of North Carolina, U. of Oklahoma Press, Thomas Uzzell, Oswald G Villard, George S Viereck, Viking Press, Samuel Van Valkenburg, Pierre Van Paassen, James Van Alen, Diane Valentine, Arejas Vitkauskas, Henry Volkening, CAV Volinhofer.
    - 2. Folder. - Wage and Hours., 1942 (Box 316)
    - 3. Folder. - W., 1942 (Box 316)
      Nym Wales, DeWitt Wallace, Honorable Henry A Wallace, Jame a H Wallace, K. Wang, Chi-Chen Wang, Roy Walford, Walter Wagner, Lenore Ward, Vernon Ward, Mrs. Richard F. Warner, CN Watkins, HA Watt, Robert Watt, Addison Webb, Wm Weber, Margaret Webster, Carl Wecks, Edward Weeks, Frank Weil, FC Weiskopf, Maxim Lieber, Otis Weise, Ruth Weiss, Genevieve Welch, MS Welch, Charles Weller, Gertrude Wellington, Carlton Wells, Fay Gillis Wells, Linton Wells, John Welsh, Gerald Wendt, Alfred Werner, Edgar Wesley, Ernest Wheeler, Mrs. Eugene Wheelock, John White, WA White, Robert Whitehand, Harold Whitnell, Margaret Widdemer, Isabel Wilder, Captain [UNK] Wilder, Roland Wiley, Tom Wilhelm, Jacob Wilk, Kenneth Skinner, Al Williams, [UNK] Laurie Williams, CT Williams, Frieda Williams, Henry Wilson, Lola Wilson, The Hon. John Winant, Rose Bigman-Mr. Winchell, Mrs. Clayton Winn, Maurice Winograd, Emanuel Winters, Robert Withington, Joseph Wittlin, Ann Wolfe, R E Wolseley, Geraldine - The Woman, Ray Wood, Dorothy Woodruff, Henry Woods, SJ Woolf, Dr. Leon Kubowitzki-World Jewish Congress, World Publishing Co., George Wosk, Hilda Wray, Richardson Wright, Ruth Jones-Writers Digest, Writer's Journal
    - 4. Folder. - X-Y-Z., 1942 (Box 316)
      SA Yorks, Eva Young, Grace Young, Lucien Zacharoff, Jake Zeitlin, Gregory Zilboorg, Dr. Zylstra.
    - 5. Folder. Lamont Controversy. (Box 316)
      Arthur Edison, Henwood, Owen Young, SJ Smitney, Frank M Millers, Thomas Lamont, Bill Benet, Harrisoh Smith, Franklin Wentworth, John F Kelleher, Cyrus Eaton, Winthrop Parkhurst, David A Bailey, Albert H Flaig, Clyde A. Mann, CF Ratham, Irwin Joseph, Rev. Edward Doane, Frances A Randolf, Nathaniel Blaisdell, Alfred Holman, WJ Euggan, David Lyle
    - 6. Folder. Mrs. Kingsley,. Bernard Shea, JJ Estabrook (Box 316)
    - 7. Folder. - A., 1943-44 (Box 316)
      Hallett Abend, Charles Abrams, Carl Ackerman, Louis Adamic, James Truslow Adams, Hervey Allen, Alfred Knopf, The American Economic Foundation, American Council on Public Affairs-Schnapper, American National Red Cross-Charles Cogging, Bert Andrews, Ben Appel, David Appel, George Arms, WP Armstrong, Nathan Ausubel, CE Ayees, Stanley Anderson, Brig, Gen. Armstrong, Olga Peterson, - American Library Association
    - 8. Folder. - B., 1943-4 (Box 316)
      Hon Joseph Ball, Hugh Beach, Maurice Basseches, Leomrd Bacon, Joseph Baker, John Barkham, Jacques Barsun, Pete Baumann, Carl Beck, Norman Bel Geddes, Silas Bent, Edward Bernays, Philip Bernstein, Struthers Burt, Mr. Van Wyck Brooks, Dan Brown, John Mason Brown, Robert Burns, Devereux Butcher, EV Biel, Abraham Bienstock, LM Birkhead, Frederick Birmingham, Charles Blanchard, Dr. Smiley Blanton, Joseph Blickensderfer, David Bowers.
    - 9. Folder. B. Cerf (letters to and from Bannett Carf), 1943-4. (Box 316)
    - 10. Folder. Conscription. (Howard Collins) (Box 316)
    - 11. Folder. Editorials. (Box 316)
    - 12. Folder. - D., 1943-4 (Box 316)
      Virginuis Dabney, Joseph Daniels, Jonathan Daniels, Jerome Davis, Wallace Duell, Bernard DeVoto, Thomas Dewey, Dorothy W Downes,
    - 13. Folder. - E., 1943-4 (Box 316)
      Roger Scaife-Encore, Winifred Eddington, Irwin Edman, Gus Edson, George F Eliot, Harris Ellsworth, Wm. Ernst, JJ Estabrook, Raymond Everitt, LC Goodrich, Mrs. AR Evans, Ronald F Eyer,
    - 14. Folder. - F., 1943-4 (Box 316)
      Clifton Fadiman, JN Sayre-Fellowship, Charles Ferguson, Marshall Field, John Gould Fletcher, John T. Flanagan, Helen Hartness Flanders, A Keith Fowler, Lawrence Frank, Jerome Frank, Barbara Fleury, George Freitag, Doris Flowers,
    - 15. Folder. - G., 1943-4 (Box 316)
      Montgomery Gambrill, LR Blanchard - Gannett Newspapers, Mrs. George Garfield, Helen A Gaubert, Donald Porter Geddes, Harry D. Gideonse, Edmund Gilligan, Dr. Sol W Ginsburg, JH Gipson, John Goette, Abel Green, Lt. Col. Roy Grinker, Antoni Gronowicz, Sara C Gross.
    - 16. Folder. - K., 1943-4 (Box 316)
      Waldemar Kaempffert, HM Kallen,
    - 17. Folder. - L., 1943-4 (Box 316)
      Loning, Walter Lippmann, HH Lippincott, Sm Levitas, Max Lerner.
  - Document Case #64. Personal and Business Correspondence.
    - 1. Folder. - M., 1943-4 (Box 316)
      BJ Mullaney, Robert Mead Jr., Dr. Karl Menninger, Francis Merchant, Isidore Meyer, Henry Allen Moe, John Mills, James Marshall, Mother McCaffrey, Robert Wetzel, Col. HS Mazet, Wilson McCutchan, Oscar McPherson, Wm McFee, Marybelle McClelland.
    - 2. Folder. -N., 1943-4 (Box 316)
      Martin Niembeller, Louis Nizer.
    - 3. Folder. O.W.I. (Box 316)
      Wallace Pratt, Harold Ickes, Ralph Gallagher, Elmer Davis, RT Haslam, The East and West Association, Negroes and the War, Women War Workers, GC Lucas, Victory Gardens, Magazine War Guide, Tale of a City, - pamphlets and correspondence from the Office of War Information.
    - 4. Folder. - P. Pierotti, 1943-4 (Box 316)
    - 5. Folder. - S., 1943-4 (Box 316)
      Emily Schossberger, Stanley Peter Silbey, Standard Oil Co. of New Jersey, Messrs. Teagle and Farish, Frank Howard, Brig. Gen. Oscar Westover,- Standard Oil Development Co., Julian Street, Sugrue.
    - 6. Folder. Jonathan Daniels - Byrd - (articles by Daniels, memos), 1945. (Box 316)
    - 7. Folder. - H-K., 1945 (Box 316)
      Lorrain Holcombe, Alfred Holloway, Raymond Holden, Henry Holt and Co., Byron Hopkins, Alphonse Heningburg, Mr. Henderson, John Hersey, Max Herzberg, Addison Hibbard, Serrell Hillman, Curtice Hitchcock, Alfred Haake, Caryl Haskins, Louis Halle Jr., [UNK] Hadden, Lawrence Hall, Walter Phelps Hall, Richard Edes Harrison, Paul Harrison, Laurance Harwood, Samuel Harrell, Chester Kerr, Leopold Koh Manuel Komroff, Robert Jackson, CM Jansky, Howard Mumford Jones, Eric Johnston, Ben H. Lambe.
    - 8. Folder. Engagements. (Box 316)
      Dublin Conference Committee, Ruby Hurley, Inauguration of Bryn Hovde, Symposium on the Problems and Tasks of International Education, The Community Churchof N.Y., Columbia Univ., Contemporary Club, Charles W Dunn, American Pharmaceutical Manufacturers Assoc., Cooper Union, The Century Club, Carteret Book Club, NAACP, The United Church, Viking Press Inc., Candor, Princeton, UN Forum, Atomic Energy Control Conference, Foreign Policy Assoc., East Tenn, Education Assoc, National Council of Teachers of English,
    - 9. Folder. Cousins - Lecture Data. (Box 316)
      Henry Canby, Milton Caniff, Melville Cane, Carl Carmer, Helen Cartier, Pierre Cartier, Mr. Jo Hubbard Chamberlin, Charlotte Observer, Stuart Chase, Sheldon Cheney, Elizabeth Schenk, Mary Anglemyer, Amy Loveman - Lee Keedick,
    - 10. Folder. - A-General., 1946 (Box 317)
      George Arms, David Adkins, John Atlee, Charles Abrams, Hamilton F Armstrong, Gay Allen, JF Albright, Rouben Abel, AM Anderson, Edward Allen, Harriet Anderson, Robert Arthur, Michael Amrine, Peter Arno, Irene Kuhn, Frank Altschul, Eddie Albert, OK Armstrong,
    - 11. Folder. Americans United Press Releases -, 1946. (Box 317)
    - 12. Folder. Americans United - Ra: Mr. Bell. (Box 317)
  - Document Case #65. Personal and Business Correspondence
    - 1. Folder. Atomic - Misc. (misc. articles and committees) (Box 317)
    - 2. Folder. Atomic Age Column - SRL. (Box 317)
      (first article appeared in issue of 11/17/45-piece by Eugene Wigner; correspondence abt. Atomic Age: Lois Clark, Mildred Fenner, Hazel Davis, John Voelker, Crate Dalton, Paul Kellogg, address by Dr. Henry DeWolf, KZ Morgan, Dr. Milton Burton, Arthur Morgan, Anno Perkins, Robert Bordner, Rev Rowland Nye, Robert Wilson,
    - 3. Folder. AU Releases. (Americans United for World Government) (Box 317)